Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications, 1930-80
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PUBLICATIONS
  - "Threshold to a Better Life: How PP Served America's Families in 1956," Annual Report, 1956 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Tips for Treasure Hunters, Campaign 1953 (Box 100, Folder 16)
  - "To be a Mother; To be a Father," By Wm. Fritz, M.D. 1965-66 undated (Box 100, Folder 17)
  - To the Children of Tomorrow 1966 (Box 100, Folder 18)
  - Tomorrow's Children 1939 (Box 100, Folder 19)
  - "To Mothers," undated (Box 100, Folder 20)
  - "Today [...] in Your Country!" Campaign 1947 (Box 100, Folder 21)
  - "To the Molly Pitchers of this War," Alabama State Health Dept., Out of Print 1943? (Box 100, Folder 22)
  - "To Those Denied a Child," 1951, 1954, 1958, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 23)
  - "The Tragedy of the Unwanted Child," By Alan F. Guttmacher, M.D. 1964 (Box 100, Folder 24)
  - "Too Many Babies," Newsweek, Reprint 1962 (Box 100, Folder 25)
  - "Too Many People," Reader's Digest, Reprint, C. Lester Walker 1948 (Box 100, Folder 26)
  - "Toward a World Population Program," International Organization, Reprint, Richard N. Gardner 1968 (Box 100, Folder 27)
  - "Trade Unionists Say Family Planning [is] In," International Ladies Garment Workers and Amalgamated Clothing Workers 1966 (Box 100, Folder 28)
  - "The Tragedy of the Unwanted Child," By A.F. Guttmacher, Reprinted from Parent's Magazine 1964 (Box 100, Folder 29)
  - "[The] Trend of the Birth Race [sic, should be "Rate"]: Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow," By Louis I. Dublin, Ph.D. 1943 (Box 100, Folder 30)
  - Truth of Birth Control, By Norman E. Himes 1931 (Box 100, Folder 31)
  - "Truth About Contraceptives," Abraham Stone, True Confessions 1955 (Box 100, Folder 32)
  - "Tuberculosis and Parenthood," Out of Print, undated (Box 100, Folder 33)
  - "[La] Tuberculosis y [La] Maternidad," 1952 (Box 100, Folder 34)
  - "Twenty-one Years' Experience with a Public Health Contraceptive Service," 1959 (Box 100, Folder 35)
  - "Twelve Months of State Contraception," 1938 (Box 100, Folder 36)
  - "Twenty Years," Sanger Research Bureau 1943 (Box 100, Folder 37)
  - "Two Billion People," Fortune, Reprint 1944 (Box 100, Folder 38)
  - "Unaccustomed as I Am," By Dorothy Hamilton Dick 1936 (Box 100, Folder 39)
  - "100 Unanswered Questions," Reprint, McCall's 1964 (Box 100, Folder 40)
  - "The Uncommon Sense of Social Research," Digest of Workshop Symposium, PPFA, Pittsburgh 1961 (Box 100, Folder 41)
  - "'Uncontrolled' Birth In Connecticut," 1951 (Box 100, Folder 42)
  - "Understanding Your Menopause," By Stella Applebaum with Nadina Kavinoky, M.D., Pub. Affairs Pamphlet #243 1959 (Box 100, Folder 43)
  - "[The] Unfinished Business of Fertility Research," International Development Review 1963 (Box 100, Folder 44)
  - "Unwanted Births and U.S. Population Growth," Larry Bumpass and Charles Westhoff, Ph.D., Perspectives 1970 (Box 100, Folder 45)
  - "[The] Unwanted Child," By Vander Veer, M.D., Out of Print 1941 (Box 100, Folder 46)
  - "Unwanted Pregnancy: A Challenge to Mental Health," By Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, Reprint, Mental Hygiene 1967 (Box 100, Folder 47)
  - "Unwanted Pregnancy Among Single Teenagers," Prepared by Research Dept. 1973? (Box 100, Folder 48)
  - "U.S. Population Growth: Would Slower be Better?" By Lawrence A. Mayer, Reprint, Fortune Magazine 1970 (Box 100, Folder 49)
  - "Ustedes Pueden Planear Su Familia," ABC's of Family Planning, Spanish, undated (Box 100, Folder 50)
  - "The Vatican and the Population Crisis," Population Reference Bureau 1965 (Box 100, Folder 51)
  - "Vaginal Diaphragm," By Hannah M. Stone, M.D. 1938 (Box 100, Folder 52)
  - Victrola Record, "Let Mrs. Sanger Speak at Your Meeting," undated (Box 100, Folder 53)
  - Victor Fund [for] International Planned Parenthood 1965, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 54)
  - Visiting Firemen, Making the Best Use of... 1954 (Box 100, Folder 55)
  - Visual Aids 1942 (Box 100, Folder 56)
  - "[The] Vital Revolution," By Norman E. Himes 1935 (Box 100, Folder 57)
  - "Voluntary Sterilization for Men and Women," and Spanish Version 1970 (Box 100, Folder 58)
  - "Volunteers Venture," Reprint, The Survey 1937 (Box 100, Folder 59)
  - Volunteer Manuals: Binghamton, NY; Mt. Kisco, NY; Cleveland 1958, undated (Box 100, Folder 60)
  - Wachsmuth Studies, "Planned Parenthood and the Businessman," 1955 (Box 100, Folder 61)
  - "Wanted...Every Baby Should Be," Poster and Pamphlet 1963 (Box 100, Folder 62)
  - "Warm Welcome," Exhibit Leaflets 1956 (Box 100, Folder 63)
  - "Wanted: 1944 Baby," 1944 (Box 100, Folder 64)
  - Washington Evening Star, Reprint, Washington D.C. 1964 (Box 100, Folder 65)
  - "Wasting Women's Lives," Reprint, New Republic 1934 (Box 100, Folder 66)
  - "We Are Planned Parenthood," 1973 (Box 100, Folder 67)
  - "We Believe," Nobel Laureates, (See Also, "Statement of Conviction") 1960 (Box 100, Folder 68)
  - "We Believe...," 1942 (Box 100, Folder 69)
  - "What are the Facts About the Population Crises?" Compiled from National Health Ed. Committee 1966 (Box 100, Folder 70)
  - "What Chicago Clergymen Say," undated (Box 100, Folder 71)
  - "What do the Women of America Think?," Reprint, Ladies Home Journal 1938 (Box 100, Folder 72)
  - "What Every Man Should Know About Birth Control," 1969 (Box 100, Folder 73)
  - "What is the Ideal Size Family?" Campaign 1952 (Box 100, Folder 74)
  - "What is Planned Parenthood?" Reprint, Pittsburgh Courier, Paul L. Jones, undated (Box 100, Folder 75)
  - "What it Means to Become a Parent," 1976 (Box 100, Folder 76)
  - "What May Health Departments Do," Haven Emerson, M.D. 1939 (Box 100, Folder 77)
  - "What of the Future," 1937 (Box 100, Folder 78)
  - "What the Planned Parenthood People Are Up To," By Glenn White, Reprint, Cosmopolitan 1965 (Box 100, Folder 79)
  - "What We Know About Sterility," Cosmopolitan Magazine, Reprint, Out of Print 1945 (Box 100, Folder 80)
  - "What Women Can Do For Peace," Reprint, Harper's Magazine, By John Fischer 1963 (Box 100, Folder 81)
  - "What's He Worth to You?" Campaign Solicitation Pamphlet 1948 (Box 100, Folder 82)
  - "When Children Ask About Sex," 1953 (Box 100, Folder 83)
  - "When More is Less: An Economic Examination of World Population and Family Planning Programs," 1968 (Box 100, Folder 84)
  - "When the Population Levels Off," By Henry Pratt Fairchild 1938 (Box 100, Folder 85)
  - "When You Plan for Your Marriage," 1956 (Box 100, Folder 86)
  - "Where Did My Money Go?" With or Without Campaign Inscription 1951 (Box 100, Folder 87)
  - "Where Do Young Families Stand on Birth Control," Redbook, Morton Sontheimer 1956 (Box 100, Folder 88)
  - "Where Population Growth Hits You," Reprint from Nation's Business 1957 (Box 100, Folder 89)
  - "A Whispered Solution," Reprint from The Wasted Americans By Edgar May, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 90)
  - White House Conference on Health, Panel Summaries, Washington D.C. 1965, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 91)
  - "Who Are They," New 1961 Fund Raising Leaflet, For Local Inserts, 1961 (Box 100, Folder 92)
  - "Why Can't We [sic, should be "You"] Have a Baby?" Dr. Guttmacher and Joan Gould 1961 (Box 100, Folder 93)
  - "Why I Favor Liberalized Abortion," Dr. Alan F. Guttmacher, Reprint, Reader's Digest 1973 (Box 100, Folder 94)
  - "Why Wait for Famous Speakers?," undated (Box 100, Folder 95)
  - "Why Women Die in Childbirth," Frederick C. Holden, M.D. 1934 (Box 100, Folder 96)
  - "Who? What? Why? How?," 1935 (Box 100, Folder 97)
  - "Why Affiliate With the American Birth Control League?," 1935 (Box 100, Folder 98)
  - "Why Americans Must Limit their Families," By Margaret Mead 1963 (Box 100, Folder 99)
  - "Will We Say, 'It Just Happened,' When the World Overpopulates Itself to Extinction?" By Joseph Lelyveld, Reprint, N.Y. Times Mag. 1970 (Box 100, Folder 100)
  - "Women, Democracy, and Birth Control," Clarence Senior, Reprint, The Humanist 1952 (Box 100, Folder 101)
  - "Women in Need of Family Planning Help," 1968 (Box 100, Folder 102)
  - "Women Speak Out in Support of Family Planning," 1973 (Box 100, Folder 103)
  - "Won't You Just Read One Page?," 1937 (Box 100, Folder 104)
  - "[The] Word You Can't Say," By Hannah Lees 1956 (Box 100, Folder 105)
  - Worker's Handbook, Campaign 1948 (Box 100, Folder 106)
  - "Working Class People and Social Work's Task," 1960 (Box 100, Folder 107)
  - "World Birth Control Challenge," By Robert Coughlan, Life 1959 (Box 100, Folder 108)
  - World Federation Plan, By Ely Culbertson 1943 (Box 100, Folder 109)
  - "World Full of People," By Harry L. Shapiro, undated (Box 100, Folder 110)
  - "[The] World's Exploding Population," Look Magazine, Reprint 1951 (Box 100, Folder 111)
  - "[The] World Has Too Many People," By Guy Irving Burch, undated (Box 100, Folder 112)
  - "World Population," By Julian Huxley 1956 (Box 100, Folder 113)
  - "World Population and Food Supply," Reprint, JAMA 1960 (Box 100, Folder 114)
  - "World Population: Growth May Surpass Food Output," N.Y. Herald Tribune 1954 (Box 100, Folder 115)
  - "Yardsticks," 1940-1944, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 116)
  - "Yes, You Can," 1969 (Box 100, Folder 117)
  - "You Can Plan Your Family," Spanish Edition, undated (Box 100, Folder 118)
  - "You Can Say When," undated (Box 100, Folder 119)
  - "Your Community is Your Business," Campaign 1947 (Box 100, Folder 120)
  - "You Plan for Everything...," Poster 1951 (Box 100, Folder 121)
  - "Your Questions Answered," 1952, 1956, 1958, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 122)
  - "Youth and Their Sexual Problems," Reprint, Journal of Clinical Child Psychology, Youth and Student Affairs 1974 (Box 100, Folder 123)
  - Old Pamphlets [Papers, Articles, Dissertations] many duplications (Box 100)
  - James Ray Adams, "Attitudinal Ambivalence and Choice of Contraceptive Method," 1961 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Rev. James E. Allen, "Family Planning Attitudes of Methodist Seminary Husbands and Wives," 1964 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - K. Back, R.Hill, J. Stycos, "Machismo in Puerto Rico, Cultural Norm and Attitude Complex," undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - John Barnes, Larry Johnson, Helen Kaufman, William Nichols, Peter Olsson, "Attitudes and Practices of Physicians Concerning Birth Control in Two California Counties," 1965 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Sidney E. Bernard, "Fatherless Families: Their Economic and Social Adjustment," 1964 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Donald J. Bogue, "The Rural South Fertility Experiments," 1966 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Barbara Brody, Progress Report: Part-time Field Workers in the Lower East Side 1966-1967 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Robert H. Browning, L.L. Parks, "Childbearing Aspirations of Public Health Maternity Patients," 1964 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Ronald Freedman, L. Coombs, "Childspacing and Family Economic Position," 1966 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Elizabeth C. Corkey, "The Birth Control Program in the Mecklenburg County Health Department," 1966 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Wylda Cowles, Steven Polgar, "Health and Communication in a Negro Census Tract," 1963 (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Kingsley Davis, "Population Policy: Will Current Programs Succeed?," 1967 (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Alice Day, Population, Poverty and the U.S. 1965 (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Elizabeth Draper, "Emotional Barriers in the Clinics," 1963 (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Betty Edmands, "A Study of Contraceptive Practices in a Selected Group of Negro Mothers in Baltimore," undated (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Stephen Enke, "Fewer Births, More Welfare," 1968? (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - Richard Frank, Christopher Tieze, "Acceptance of an Oral Contraceptive Program in a Large Metropolitan Area," 1965 (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - Sidney Furie, "Birth Control and the Lower-class Unmarried Mother," 1966 (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - Alan F. Guttmacher, "National Motives for Birth Control," 1966 (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - David M. Heer, "Economic Development and Fertility," 1965 (Box 102, Folder 20)
  - Studies in Family Planning, Pop. Council 1966, 1968, undated (Box 102, Folder 21)
  - F. Jaffe, S. Polgar, "Medical Indications for Fertility Control," 1963 (Box 102, Folder 22)
  - William C. Jenne, "A Factor Analysis of Some Social and Demographic Variables Related to Planned Parenthood," 1958 (Box 102, Folder 23)
  - J. William Leasure, "Some Economic Benefits of Birth Prevention," 1967 (Box 102, Folder 24)
  - Hans Lehfelt, E.W. Kulka, H.G. Liebmann, "Comparative Study of Intrauterine Contraceptive Devices," 1965 (Box 102, Folder 25)
  - E. James Lieberman, "Preventive Psychiatry and Family Planning," 1964 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - H. Farrand Livingston, Elizabeth Livingston, "The Implications of Unwanted Pregnancies Among Public Assistance Recipients," 1964 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Gitta Meier, "The Need for Family Planning," 1961 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Hannah D. Mitchell, "How Do I Talk? -Family Planning," 1966 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Dorothy L. Nortman, The Population Problem 1965 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Gerard Piel, "Comprehensive Community Health Services for New York City," undated (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Edward Pohlman, "Unwanted Conceptions: Research on Undesirable Consequences," 1965 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Steven Polgar, "Sociocultural Research in Family Planning in the United States: Review and Prospects," 1966 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Martin Rein, Community Acceptance of the Planned Parenthood Program 1961 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Frank Reissman, "Strategies and Suggestions for Training Nonprofessionals," 1966 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - "Evaluating Democratic Control Programs," John A. Ross 1966 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Maurice V. Russell, "A Demonstration Project in Fertility Control," 1964 (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Alice S. Rossi, "Abortion Laws and Their Victims," undated (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Andrew Collver, R.T. Have, Mary C. Speare, "Factors Influencing the Use of Maternal Health Services," 1967 (Box 103, Folder 14)
  - J. Mayone Stycos, "Catholicism and Birth Control in the Western Hemisphere," 1967 (Box 103, Folder 15)
  - Clark E. Vincent, "The 'Hard-to-Reach' Poverty Level Females in Birth Control Programs," undated (Box 103, Folder 16)
  - Joseph S. Zeisel, "Impact of Population Growth on Employment," 1963 (Box 103, Folder 17)
  - M 9628 - Hlth. Lo. Inc. Fams. N.Y.C., "The Impact of Medical Discoveries on Family Health in Low-Income Neighborhoods of New York," 1965 (Box 103, Folder 18)
  - "The Impact of New Contraceptive Methods in Impoverished Neighborhoods of N.Y.," M-9078 1965 (Box 103, Folder 19)
  - M-9553, "Evolution and the Ills of Mankind," Polgar 1965 (See also Drawer #9) (Box 103, Folder 20)
  - M-8629, Difficulties of Reaching Low-Income Women: Home Visiting Project Mt. Vernon, N.Y. 1964 (Box 103, Folder 21)
  - M-8464, "Values and Contraception Among Urban Negroes with Moderate Incomes," Polgar 1964 (Box 103, Folder 22)
  - "An Experiment in Family Planning Service in Low Income Neighborhoods in N.Y.C.," App.I, M-8307 1964 (Box 103, Folder 23)
  - "Family Planning Attitudes of Methodist Seminary Husbands and Wives," by James E. Allen 1963 (Box 103, Folder 24)
  - "United States: Methods of Fertility Control," 1955, 1960, 1965, 1967 (Box 103, Folder 25)
  - "The United States: The Pill and The Birth Rate, 1960-1965," 1967 (Box 103, Folder 26)
  - "A New Chapter in Family Planning," Polgar 1965 (Box 103, Folder 27)
  - "Health Action in Cross-Cultural Perspective," Polgar, undated (Box 103, Folder 28)
  - M-3073, Corkey (Mecklenburg Health Dept., N.C.), Report on B.C. 1962 (Box 103, Folder 29)
  - Rossi, Lower Cl. Motiv., M-1435 ["Birth Control and the Motivations of the Lower Class," 1961 (Box 103, Folder 30)
  - M-457, "Working Class People and Social Work's Task," by Handel and Rainwater 1960 (Box 103, Folder 31)
  - M-458, "Social Class and the American Social System," Martin B. Loeb, Ph.D., U.Cal., L.A. 1960 (Box 103, Folder 32)
  - Gitta Meier, Research and Action Program in Human Fertility Control: A Review, Various Articles 1961-1965 (Box 103, Folder 33)
  - A.F.G.: Therapeutic Abortion 1963, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 34)
  - Hatcher: Public Health 1969 (Box 103, Folder 35)
  - Family Planning Programs Abroad 1966? (Box 103, Folder 36)
  - R. Day: Factors Influencing Offspring, 2.15, 1967 (Box 103, Folder 37)
  - Hartman: 100 Questions, Human Reproduction 1964 (Box 103, Folder 38)
  - N.T. Gray: Welfare's Responsibility 1966 (Box 103, Folder 39)
  - Jennie F. Scheller, "Implications of Family Planning for Social Work Intervention," 1965 (Box 103, Folder 40)
  - Nicholas Guy Maklary, "Contraception and Abortion," 1969 (Box 103, Folder 41)
  - Sociocultural Research in Family Planning in U.S., Various Articles 1961, 1966-67 (Box 103, Folder 42)
  - "Birth Control and Nose Counting," Steven Polgar 1966 (Box 103, Folder 43)
  - Public Communication About Birth Control, Carol Jones Whitcraft 1966 (Box 103, Folder 44)
  - Articles with PPWP Library Aid 1966-1967 (Box 103, Folder 45)